usafisnews.org 2009-03-18

# Usafis Green Card Lottery Application Service Online | Privacy Policy

Version 2.1 – (Last updated December 6, 2006)

Information Collection and Use

_Usafis Organization_ is the sole owner of the information collected on this site, usafis.org. _Usafis Organization_ will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. _Usafis Organization_ collects information from our users at several different points on _Usafis Organization_ website. 

Order

_Usafis Organization_ request information from the user on order form. Here a user must provide contact information (like name and address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer's orders. If _Usafis Organization_ have trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with the user. After purchasing the service, the user is asked to provide personal details such as gender, marital status, place of birth (country, province and city), date of birth, mailing address and provide a photo. Same details required for spouse and unmarried children under 21 years of age.

Use of Cookies

_Usafis Organization_ uses cookies to gather and store information. Cookies are pieces of data that a web site transfers to user computer's hard drive solely for record-keeping purposes. Cookies help _Usafis Organization_ make its software more useful by storing information on your preferences. There is nothing unusual about the use of cookies by a web site and they are an industry standard. They do not personally identify you, but they will identify your computer. Your browser is most likely set up to accept cookies, but you can set yours to refuse them. If you do so, you may not be able to take full advantage of _Usafis Organization_ 's web site. _Usafis Organization_ is not liable for any failure of your computer due to their use of cookies. There are two type of cookies used during surfing of the website: session cookies and persistent (non-session) cookies. Those cookies are used to keep record of the referring site (if any) and to maintain integrity of service throughout the purchasing process.

Log Files

_Usafis Organization_ use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

Sharing

_Usafis Organization_ share aggregated demographic information with partners. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. _Usafis Organization_ use an outside shipping company and a credit card processing company to bill users for services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. _Usafis Organization_ partner with another party to provide legal consultancy, publications and software. When the user signs up for these services, _Usafis Organization_ will share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. These parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services. 

_Usafis Organization_ may provide your email information to selected partners, reputable companies or organizations whose products and services may interest you. If Usafis Organization discloses personally identifiable information to third-party companies who want to market products or services to you, it will provide you with an opportunity to opt out or block such uses. In addition, Usafis Organization may share personally identifiable information with selected 3rd parties, and may utilize the services of 3rd party marketing partners to combine additional information from these 3rd parties with the collected personal information. These 3rd parties may send you offers via online marketing. If you prefer not to receive online marketing information from Usafis Organization or third-party companies, please contact online [through this link.](http://www.usafis.org/helpdesk)

Links

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that _Usafis Organization_ is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. _Usafis Organization_ encourage users to be aware when they leave this site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site. 

Surveys & Contests

From time-to-time _Usafis Organization_ site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.

Tell-A-Friend

If a user elects to use _Usafis Organization_ referral service for informing a friend about this site, we ask them for the friend's name and email address. _Usafis Organization_ will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. The friend may contact _Usafis Organization_ to request the removal of the information from the database [through this link](http://www.usafis.org/helpdesk). 

Security

This website takes every precaution to protect users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, the information is protected both online and off-line. When registration form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as the payment reply form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked. 

Special Offers

_Usafis Organization_ send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users _Usafis Organization_ present the option to not receive these types of communications. See “Choice/Opt-out” below.

Correction/Updating Personal Information:

If a user's personally identifiable information changes, or if a user no longer desires _Usafis Organization_ service, _Usafis Organization_ will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove that user's personal data provided to _Usafis Organization_. This can usually be done at the member information page or by notifying _Usafis Organization_ Customer Support at http://www.usafis.org/helpdesk/.

Choice/Opt-out

_Usafis Organization_ users are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having their information used for purposes not directly related to _Usafis Organization_ site. In order to unsubscribe you may type your email address at http://www.usafis.org/unsubscribe/ and your request will be recorded on our database.

Legal Disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site

Testimonial

Usafis testimonials page present winners who wanted to share their success stories with others. Usafis post customer testimonials on our web site, which may contain personally identifiable information such as the customer's name or other details, all in accordance with customer's explicit prior consent. We always obtain customer's consent prior to posting the testimonial, to post their personal information along with their testimonial. 

Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.
